Hello everyone and welcome back to English
Pod. My name is Marco and my name is
Catherine and it's the holiday season so
that means more Christmas songs for you
guys. That's right and today we're
going to be taking a look at a very famous
song, very relaxed but very beautiful
song called Silent Night. Yeah this is
one of those songs that you hear
everywhere but unlike jingle bells which is
like dingle bells, dingle bell, not you
know, vegetarian, uplifting and shopping
music. This is more as Marco said
calm, peaceful, almost church music so
we're going to find out what the words
mean in this very classic song. Right it's
classic and very religious because it
has a connotation towards the Catholic
religion. So why don't we listen to the
song and then we'll be back to explain it.
[Music]
All right we're back so now let's take
a look at this song line by line so we're
not going to do the standard format of
picking out words. We're going to do it
but line by line to kind of get a good
feel for this dialogue. So first of all
some background. Okay so the 24th the
evening Marian Joseph are looking for a
place to stay Mary the Virgin mother
of God is going to give birth to a baby.
Right. And they need a place to stay
so finally they find a place it's not a
hotel it's not a house it's like an inn.
Yeah well it's actually the stables for
the inn. And so what the song is celebrating
is what happens afterwards after the
baby Jesus is born so that's where we are.
All right so the first line says
silent night holy night. All right
you know it's holy that means it's
religiously special it's important.
Okay all is calm all is bright.
So we talk about bright lights sometimes
something is bright if it it gives a lot of
light off. And well the next line is
very interesting because it says round
young virgin mother and child. Now you
see this first two words there round yawn.
What is roundy yawn? So round comes
from around. Okay yawn means over there.
So around over there so over there
we've got two people. Okay we've over there
we've got the Virgin mother and her child.
Okay so the Virgin mother is
married right. That's right. And the
child would be Jesus. Exactly. And this is
holy infant so tender and mild. Okay
so what is an infant? An infant is a baby
some some baby that's just been born
so we can say that infants are very very
delicate. You have to be very careful
when you'll hold an infant. But in this
case a holy infant is Jesus he's special
for religious reasons. Okay and when
they say that he's tender and mild
what does he mean by that? Well you talk
about tender things when you're
talking about things that are soft okay
delicate gentle or sweet. Okay and
something that is mild or someone that is
mild is very quiet and calm and
gentle. So not making much noise.
So the baby was is very sweet very tender
and wasn't crying or making a big you know
fuss. Exactly. And then we have a sleep
in heavenly peace sleep in heavenly peace.
Well the baby's quiet because the
baby's sleeping. So you're saying sleep and
heavenly peace that means you know
made a piece of heaven because heaven is a
very peaceful place. The most peaceful
place. May that peace be with you when
you're sleeping. Okay very good.
Right and moving on we have Silent Night
Holy Night again. But then they say
shepherds quake at the site. So what is this?
Shepherds we know that these are people
that take care of sheep. That's right
they make the sheep move from one place
to another. And but it says they quake
at the site. So they quake at the site of
what? Well quake we often say quiver in
one's boots or too quake means to shake
when you're nervous. Okay so you know
when you're going to make a speech
in front of many many many people your
hands start to shake that's called
quaking. Okay so too quake. All right.
So shepherds quake they're nervous at the
site. Well the site is the noun for seeing
something. The site of Jesus. The baby.
Okay. Glories stream from heaven a
far. So glories stream from heaven a far.
Okay the verb here. The action word is
too streamed. Okay that means to come down.
Okay so to come down and kind of big
amounts. So we have glory. Glory.
So happiness and joy and glory and good
things coming down from the heaven.
So lots of positive good things coming down
from heaven. And where is heaven? A far.
A far. So the key part of this is the
word far. It's far away right? Yeah.
A far is an old word we used to describe
something that's far away. So the heavens
of far or the the heavens that are far
away are giving us all of this joy and
happiness. Okay glory. And then the song
says heavenly hosts sing Alleluia.
So heavenly hosts those are bodies or
people or spirits in the sky. Angels
they're singing Alleluia. So Alleluia is a
word that we often use in the Christian
religion that comes from Greek actually.
Oh really? Yeah. So Alleluia is a
Greek word and it means celebrate joy.
Amen. Okay Alleluia. It's something you're
happy about. Alleluia. Alleluia. And then
they say Christ the Savior is born.
Now we have this the Savior. What is it?
Who is a Savior? Or what is a Savior?
It's a very good question. The Savior is a
where we only read well we don't hear
that often but you've heard the word to
save before. So for example, I fell into
the water and Marco jumped in and saved me.
So I would be a Savior. Marco
was my Savior. He saved me.
But in this case, Savior refers to the Bible
and the things that Jesus did later. So
we say in Christianity, he saved people.
There's even in kind. So he is the Savior.
All right. Christ the Savior. All
right. And then our next verse it says
Silent Night Holy Night. Son of God
loves pure light. Radiant beings from
thy holy face. So we have radiant
beams and then we have this word thigh.
So these beams is like a beam of light,
right? It's like a line of light but you
know how how light is clear. So a
beam of light is something that that comes
down in a straight line. You can see it.
You can see it. So for example, when I
turn on a flashlight and there's a
line of light, that's a beam. Okay.
And radiant means it's very it means it's
very bright. It's very clear. Clear and
it's strong and it's coming out from
that one place. Okay. And what about this
word thigh? It's very popular like form
old English, right? It's an old English
form of saying you you. Right. So in
the olden days in English, we had different
ways of saying the word you. Okay.
And so thigh is one of those words. And you
hear this very often. And so in this
sentence, we're saying radiant beams from
thy holy face, we're now starting to talk
to Jesus because we're referring to him.
You radiant beams light
is coming out of your face.
Your voice is such a holy. Now, I think
you can probably see this thigh and
vow in Shakespeare,
for example, right?
Exactly. Shakespeare,
the Bible, prayers, and
all sorts of old books and poetry. Okay.
And then we say with the dawn of
redeeming grace. So what is to redeem? To
redeem is to find value in something that
didn't have value before. Okay. Okay.
So maybe I have a ticket for some, okay, I
want a small lottery ticket, $5. I go to
the store to redeem my money. Okay. The
paper is worthless. Right. But it's worth
something when I redeem it. Okay. Okay. So
Christ the Redeemer, when he saves people,
he redeems them. Okay. He gives them value
again. Very good. So it's a very profound
song, right? And it talks about as we say
about Jesus, about angels and it's
very, very religious. So it's a great song
and it's, well, it's a very popular song.
And well, even if you don't share the
religious connotation that the song
has, it still is very popular in North
America and many parts of the world.
So why don't we have a listen to this song
one last time.
round the unverged
and mother and child.
Oh, we infant, so tender
and mild. Sleep in and out.
[music]
So when I was a little girl at
school, we had to sing this in German.
So I know that there
are some other countries
that have the same
song with some words.
Yeah, so it's the same rhythm
and everything but just in German.
And is it just pretty much the
same idea, the same words?
Yeah, almost exactly the
same, just in the translated form.
So maybe it came from German, I don't know.
Because it seems to
be pretty old, right?
But it is a very common
song during Christmas.
And even many times, Christmas
carolers will go around in an
neighborhood and sing these
songs in different places, right?
Exactly. And it's a
really beautiful song.
One of my favorites. And
I'm not a religious person.
So I don't really like it for the
religious perspective that it gave us.
But I do think that it's
just one of those beautiful
classic songs that makes
the season very warm.
The music is nice in the song.
All right, so an interesting
song and I'm sure we're
going to have a lot of
questions and comments about it.
So we expect to see you
guys on our website, www.
EnglishPod.com and
we'll see you guys there.
Happy holidays and enjoy. Bye-bye.
[Music]